const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 6-year-old boy came to the outpatient department (OPD) with a complaint of short stature. On examination, his height is 92 cm and the X-ray shows bullet-like carpal bones. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Celiac disease","bool":false},{"option":"Mucopolysaccharidoses","bool":true},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Aspirin generally should be avoided as an anti-inflammatory drug in gout because it counteracts the effect of which of the following drugs that is used in a hyperuricemic patient?","answers":[{"option":"Probenecid","bool":true},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":false},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Indomethacin","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the best imaging modality for assessment of bone mineral density?","answers":[{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"DEXA scan","bool":true},{"option":"Plain X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Cupping, splaying, and fraying of the lower end of the radius are seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Healed fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":true},{"option":"Scurvy","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following cells are responsible to regulate bone matrix formation and bone mineralization?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoblasts","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoclasts","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoclast precursor","bool":false},{"option":"Periosteal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following can be caused by inhalation of coal dust?","answers":[{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":true},{"option":"Farmerâ€™s lung","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by ionizing radiation, X-rays, and radioactive isotopes?","answers":[{"option":"Bulimia","bool":false},{"option":"Anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Polycythemia","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":true},{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What will be the primary cause of death from massive acetaminophen overdose?","answers":[{"option":"AV conduction disturbance","bool":false},{"option":"Acute nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Liver failure","bool":true},{"option":"Status asthmaticus","bool":false},{"option":"Status epilepticus","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 2-year-old child is suspected with rickets, what important X-ray would you advice for this child?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray skull","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray wrist (PA view)","bool":true},{"option":"X-ray both wrist (lateral view)","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray right knee","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray chest (PA view)","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which bone is most commonly involved in osteoblastoma?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Femur","bool":false},{"option":"Skull","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebrae","bool":true},{"option":"Humerus","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is a treatment of acute gout?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium carbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Bisphosphonates","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":true},{"option":"Denosumab","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following diseases may cause hypouricemia?","answers":[{"option":"Von Gierke disease","bool":false},{"option":"Tumor lysis syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"HGPRT deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"ADA deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Lesch-Nyhan syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Sabre shin is a feature of congenital syphilis. Which part of the tibia is typically affected?","answers":[{"option":"Postero-lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Antero-posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Postero-medial","bool":false},{"option":"Antero-medial","bool":true},{"option":"Antero-lateral","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Patients with osteoarthritis may develop bony swellings at the distal interphalangeal (DIP) and proximal interphalangeal (PIP) joints. What are the swellings at DIP joints called?","answers":[{"option":"Swan neck deformity","bool":false},{"option":"Trigger finger","bool":false},{"option":"Bouchard nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Boutonniere","bool":false},{"option":"Heberden nodes","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is a common early complication of a supracondylar fracture of the humerus?","answers":[{"option":"Radial artery damage","bool":false},{"option":"Elbow stiffness","bool":false},{"option":"Volkmann's contracture","bool":false},{"option":"Brachial artery damage","bool":true},{"option":"Ulnar nerve injury","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A food industry is suspected of dumping its water in the local river. Which of the following is the best way to detect the quality of water in this river in order to confirm or deny the suspicion?","answers":[{"option":"Softness of water","bool":false},{"option":"Dirt content of water","bool":false},{"option":"Temperature of water","bool":false},{"option":"Dissolved carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Biochemical oxygen demand","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the best investigation to determine the causative organism in a patient with osteomyelitis?","answers":[{"option":"CBC","bool":false},{"option":"Bone biopsy or aspiration with culture","bool":true},{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"MRI","bool":false},{"option":"ESR and CRP","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A child is diagnosed with rickets. What is the standard treatment for him?","answers":[{"option":"1 lacs to 2 lacs IU vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"6000-12000 IU vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Stoss therapy 3-6 lacs IU IM","bool":true},{"option":"Stoss therapy 2-3 lacs IM","bool":false},{"option":"3000-6000 IU vitamin D","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"In osteomyelitis, what is the new bone formed around the infected bone called?","answers":[{"option":"Sequestrum","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous bone","bool":false},{"option":"Scar","bool":false},{"option":"Involucrum","bool":true},{"option":"Cortical bone","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs causes systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrocortisone","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclophosphamide","bool":false},{"option":"Minocycline","bool":true},{"option":"Sodium aurothiomalate","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 30-year-old female is brought to the emergency room following a generalized seizure. She is on medications for systemic lupus erythematosus for the past year since her diagnosis. This is the fourth episode of fits she has had in the past 2 weeks. What medication should the patient be given?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroids with methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous methylprednisolone","bool":true},{"option":"Methotrexate 15 mg daily orally","bool":false},{"option":"Non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Hydroxychloroquine 400 mg weekly","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Increased concentration of toxins in the environment along the food chain, particularly aquatic life is known as?","answers":[{"option":"Bioaccumulation","bool":false},{"option":"Biomagnification","bool":true},{"option":"Environmental stratification","bool":false},{"option":"Eutrophication","bool":false},{"option":"Thermal stratification","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 25-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with pain in the small joints of her hand associated with a peculiar butterfly-shaped rash over her cheeks and nose. She was diagnosed with systemic lupus erythematosus 6 months back. On examination, the interphalangeal joints are swollen and painful. Urine detailed report is negative for proteins. What treatment should be given to this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Oral corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclophosphamide","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Avoid sun exposure + anti malarials + celecoxib","bool":true},{"option":"Intravenous prednisolone","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Femoral fractures in young infants and children are best managed by?","answers":[{"option":"Perkin's traction","bool":false},{"option":"Halo pelvic traction","bool":false},{"option":"Dunlop traction","bool":false},{"option":"Crutch field traction","bool":false},{"option":"Gallow's traction","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which one of the following is a late complication of supracondylar fractures?","answers":[{"option":"Entrapment of brachial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Stiffness","bool":true},{"option":"Compartment syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve damage","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is a complication of humeral shaft fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Avascular necrosis of the humerus","bool":false},{"option":"Winged scapula","bool":false},{"option":"Haematoma formation","bool":false},{"option":"Median nerve syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Radial nerve syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is a complication of crush syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Renal failure","bool":true},{"option":"Myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Liver failure","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is used for the treatment of acute gout?","answers":[{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":true},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":false},{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"In which pattern is Duchenne muscular dystrophy inherited?","answers":[{"option":"X linked dominant","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant","bool":false},{"option":"X linked recessive","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is not removed by roll boiling of water?","answers":[{"option":"Germs","bool":false},{"option":"Cysts","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Metals","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of primary osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Gender","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic","bool":true},{"option":"Obesity","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 30-year-old boxer presents with progressively increasing back pain, faecal and urinary incontinence. On examination, perineal sensations are also decreased. The patient is fully conscious and oriented to the surroundings. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanical low back pain","bool":false},{"option":"Spondylosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Spinal stenosis","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 55-year-old female, para 11+2, presents to the outpatient clinic with bilateral knee and back pain for the past 6 months. The doctor recommends an investigation for determining the bone mineral density. What is the investigation of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Dual-energy x-ray absorptiometry (DEXA)","bool":true},{"option":"Bone scan","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT) scan","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A female has developed paresthesia and tetany after undergoing thyroid surgery. What is the cause of these symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperparathyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Euthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoparathyroidism","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 36-year-old female presents to her physician with difficulty combing her hair and muscle weakness for the past year. Chest examination reveals bilateral coarse crackles. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Polymyositis","bool":true},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":false},{"option":"Dermatomyositis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Reiter's syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following features differentiates dermatomyositis from polymyositis?","answers":[{"option":"Skin involvement","bool":true},{"option":"Liver involvement","bool":false},{"option":"Joint involvement","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple muscle involvement","bool":false},{"option":"Lung involvement","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 30-year-old female presents to the physician with chronic progressive difficulty in getting up from the floor during her daily prayers. Her complaint is associated with peculiar rashes on the face and eyelids for 4-months. Examination reveals bilateral proximal muscle weakness. Muscle biopsy taken from the biceps femoris muscle will most likely show what histopathological finding?","answers":[{"option":"Perifascicular atrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Intrafascicular inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Fascicular lymphocytes and B cells","bool":false},{"option":"Capillary inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils and lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 2-year-old boy has presented with multiple fractures and blue sclera. His brother has a similar condition. What is your diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":true},{"option":"Marfan Syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Osteitis deformans","bool":false},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Hurler syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"An athlete is lying unconscious, which of the following is essential in saving his life?","answers":[{"option":"Check pupils","bool":false},{"option":"Check temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Check hydration status","bool":true},{"option":"Ask him where he is","bool":false},{"option":"Ask his name","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the most life-threatening electrolyte imbalance seen in athletes?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatermia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypercalcaemia","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Injury to which of the following results in a mallet finger?","answers":[{"option":"Extensor of wrist","bool":false},{"option":"Extensor of distal interphalangeal joint","bool":true},{"option":"Extensors of proximal interphalangeal joint","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor of proximal interphalangeal joint","bool":false},{"option":"Flexors of distal interphalangeal joint","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following inhibits purine synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"AMP","bool":true},{"option":"UMP","bool":false},{"option":"GDP","bool":false},{"option":"ATP","bool":false},{"option":"ADP","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Accumulation of which of the following pollutants leads to the blue-baby syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Nitrites","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrates","bool":true},{"option":"Persistent organic pollutants (POP's)","bool":false},{"option":"Heavy metals","bool":false},{"option":"DDT","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"X-ray of a 10-year-old boy shows an incidental finding of a central lytic lesion in the upper humerus. What is the probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Aneurysmal bone cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Unicameral bone cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Paget disease","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the principal indication for the measurement of serum anti-CCP antibodies in rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"To assess severity","bool":false},{"option":"To diagnose RA","bool":true},{"option":"To see treatment","bool":false},{"option":"To assess prognosis","bool":false},{"option":"To predict survival","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 12-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of pain when opening his mouth and while chewing food. He is diagnosed with sclerosing osteomyelitis of GarrÃ©. Which of the following bones is typically involved in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Mandible","bool":true},{"option":"Small bones of hand and feet","bool":false},{"option":"Knee","bool":false},{"option":"Femur","bool":false},{"option":"Skull bones","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 60-year-old woman presents with inter-trochanteric fracture of the femur. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Hemi-arthroplasty","bool":false},{"option":"Dynamic hip screw (DHS)","bool":true},{"option":"External fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Internal fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Plaster cast and antibiotics","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"According to Erikson's psychosocial theory of development, a man satisfied with his life will have:","answers":[{"option":"Acceptance","bool":false},{"option":"Happiness","bool":false},{"option":"Internal satisfaction","bool":false},{"option":"Relief","bool":false},{"option":"Integrity","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 60-year-old woman presents with an intracapsular hip fracture. She is very fragile and has major comorbidities, how will you treat her?","answers":[{"option":"Hemi-arthroplasty","bool":true},{"option":"External fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Total hip replacement","bool":false},{"option":"Hip screws","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and internal fixation (ORIF)","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 5-year-old girl presents with a vaginal mass. What is the most likely condition?","answers":[{"option":"Adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoma","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body","bool":false},{"option":"Rhabdomyosarcoma","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Anti Jo-1 antibodies are associated with which lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Pleurisy","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory distress","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the angle of the knee joint in healthy individuals?","answers":[{"option":"17Â° valgus","bool":false},{"option":"70Â° valgus","bool":false},{"option":"100Â° valgus","bool":false},{"option":"7Â° valgus","bool":true},{"option":"7Â° varus","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is not co-prescribed with aspirin in gout?","answers":[{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Indomethacin","bool":false},{"option":"Probenecid","bool":true},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 7-year-old child has sustained a forearm fracture while playing. A radiograph has been performed, and a diagnosis of a stable right radioulnar fracture is made. What will be the most appropriate management of this child?","answers":[{"option":"Intramedullary nailing","bool":false},{"option":"Closed reduction and casting","bool":true},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false},{"option":"K-wire","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and fixation","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the management of undisplaced fracture of the middle third of the clavicle?","answers":[{"option":"Skull traction","bool":false},{"option":"External fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Sling and conservative management","bool":true},{"option":"Casting","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and internal fixation","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"An X-ray of a patient shows a distal radius fracture with volar displacement. What is this fracture called?","answers":[{"option":"Montaggiea fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Colle's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Smith's fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Radius fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Galezzia fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the end-product of purine metabolism?","answers":[{"option":"Uric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Uracil","bool":false},{"option":"Guanine","bool":false},{"option":"Ammonia","bool":false},{"option":"Urea","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following features differentiates polymyositis from dermatomyositis?","answers":[{"option":"Myalgia is seen in only one of them","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle weakness is seen only in polymyositis","bool":false},{"option":"One of them is an immunological disease","bool":false},{"option":"One of them shows myopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Cutaneous features are only seen in dermatomyositis","bool":true}]},{"id":58,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the first choice DMARD for a patient with rheumatoid arthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Leflunomide","bool":false},{"option":"Azathioprine","bool":false},{"option":"Gold salts","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":true},{"option":"Hydroxychloroquine","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"An 8-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with complaints of pain and swelling in his lower right leg. Past history is remarkable for compound open fracture of tibia and fibula of the same leg 1 year ago. The fracture was treated using an external fixator and the skin was sutured. The x-ray of the affected limb will most likely show which of the following findings?","answers":[{"option":"Bone mass with bone destruction","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical nidus with surrounding sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Involucrum and sequestrum","bool":true},{"option":"Soft tissue hemorrhage and swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Bone loss and osteoporosis","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Spilled teacup sign is seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Lunate dislocation","bool":true},{"option":"Scaphoid dislocation","bool":false},{"option":"Scaphoid fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Pisiform fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Hamate dislocation","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 69-year-old female has presented with a wrist fracture. She had menopause at the age of 52. She also had a wrist fracture 2 years back. What treatment will you give her along with fracture treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Hormone replacement therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Bisphosphonates","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium supplements","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 7-year-old child is brought to the clinic for the evaluation of short stature. Physical examination reveals corneal clouding and hepatosplenomegaly. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hurler syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Marfan Syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hunter Syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Osteogenesis imperfecta","bool":false},{"option":"Achondroplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the term used for unmineralized bone matrix?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoclasts","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoma","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoid","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is not associated with bone resorption?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen and progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone only","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen only","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 60-year-old woman with fractures presents to the office, she had been taking long-term steroids, how do we treat her?","answers":[{"option":"Lifestyle modification","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D + calcium supplementation","bool":false},{"option":"Bisphosphonates + vitamin D + calcium","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Cast for fractures","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A radiologist labels a lesion on an X-ray of the femur as \"lytic focus surrounded by a zone of sclerosis\". Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Aneurysmal bone cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Chondrosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":true},{"option":"Ewing sarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of these factors is responsible for absorption of phosphorus from the intestine?","answers":[{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false},{"option":"Ionized calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Osteoarthritis is what type of joint disease?","answers":[{"option":"Generative","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory","bool":false},{"option":"Regenerative","bool":false},{"option":"Degenerative","bool":true},{"option":"Autoimmune","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Ankylosing Spondylitis most frequently affects which joint?","answers":[{"option":"Finger","bool":false},{"option":"Hip","bool":false},{"option":"Knee","bool":false},{"option":"Sacroiliac","bool":true},{"option":"Vertebral","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 35-year-old patient comes to the outpatient department with the complaint of sudden joint pain and severe tenderness around the joint. He further told the doctor that his joint was swollen, warm to the touch, and skin color changes to red around the joint. Needle aspiration was done and a pseudogout diagnosis was made. Which of the following joint is most likely to involved?","answers":[{"option":"Wrist","bool":false},{"option":"Knee","bool":true},{"option":"Elbow","bool":false},{"option":"Shoulder","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Twisting of bone along its long axis leads to which kind of fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Greenstick fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Transverse fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Twist fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"How is a Colle's fracture managed?","answers":[{"option":"Open reduction and internal fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Bone graft","bool":false},{"option":"Intramedullary nailing","bool":false},{"option":"Manipulation and casting","bool":true},{"option":"External fixation","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"According to the Salter-Harris classification, which fracture type leads to complete growth arrest?","answers":[{"option":"Type 2","bool":false},{"option":"Type 5","bool":true},{"option":"Type 4","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the key clinical feature to differentiate degenerative joint changes from inflammatory joint changes?","answers":[{"option":"Crepitus","bool":true},{"option":"Instability","bool":false},{"option":"Redness","bool":false},{"option":"Warmth","bool":false},{"option":"Tenderness","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Open fractures are best managed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"External fixation","bool":true},{"option":"Intramedullary nailing","bool":false},{"option":"Plating","bool":false},{"option":"Internal fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Plaster of paris","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Skull traction is used for which kind of spine fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Coccyx","bool":false},{"option":"Sacral","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar","bool":false},{"option":"Thoracic","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 50-year-old presents to the physician because of a 4-month history of back pain. He notes that the pain is relieved by stooping forward. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Spondylosis","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal stenosis","bool":true},{"option":"Spondylitis","bool":false},{"option":"Disc prolapse","bool":false},{"option":"Disc herniation","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following statement is true regarding disease-modifying anti-rheumatic drugs (DMARDs)?","answers":[{"option":"Used for relief of acute symptoms","bool":false},{"option":"They do not induce remission","bool":false},{"option":"Should be started after a waiting time of 6 months","bool":false},{"option":"Slow the destruction of bone in RA","bool":true},{"option":"Monotherapy can be used for moderate RA","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of allopurinol?","answers":[{"option":"Xanthine oxidase inhibitor","bool":true},{"option":"Xanthine oxidase analogue","bool":false},{"option":"Increases uric acid secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthine reductase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Folate reductase inhibitor","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What are the effects of radiation in the eye?","answers":[{"option":"Cataract","bool":true},{"option":"Glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"Conjuctivitis","bool":false},{"option":"Keratitis","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior uveitis","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What are the stages of osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Early, middle, late","bool":false},{"option":"Early, moderate, severe, very severe","bool":false},{"option":"Normal, severe, moderate","bool":false},{"option":"Mild, severe, very severe","bool":false},{"option":"Mild, moderate, severe","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Slow sand filter is differentiated from rapid sand filter by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Clay","bool":false},{"option":"Sediment","bool":false},{"option":"Sand","bool":false},{"option":"Filters","bool":false},{"option":"Zoogleal layer","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 40-year-old man presents to the emergency department with a swollen, exquisitely painful big toe. The attending physician started intravenous fluids and indomethacin, making a provisional diagnosis of gout. However, he fails to improve. The patient is afebrile, and no other joint is involved. His mother arrives and gave a detailed history, that he had few episodes of bloody diarrhea a few weeks back for which they took treatment from a local doctor. Hearing this, the doctor immediately changed his differential. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudogout","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the characteristic histological finding found in Paget's disease of bone?","answers":[{"option":"Pannus","bool":false},{"option":"Blue sclera","bool":false},{"option":"Giant osteoclasts","bool":false},{"option":"Osteophytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mosaic pattern","bool":true}]},{"id":85,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding the use of methotrexate during pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Stop in the third trimester","bool":false},{"option":"Stop 3 months after delivery","bool":false},{"option":"Stop in the first trimester","bool":false},{"option":"Stop 3 months before conception","bool":true},{"option":"Continue use during pregnancy","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs can be given in acute gout?","answers":[{"option":"Colchicine","bool":true},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 3-day old baby presents with club foot. What would be the ideal first-line management for him?","answers":[{"option":"Serial casting","bool":true},{"option":"Immediate surgery","bool":false},{"option":"No treatment- reassure parents that this will get better on its own","bool":false},{"option":"Physiotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Open reduction and internal fixation","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the permissible E coli limit for safe drinking water?","answers":[{"option":"5 E. coli/100ml","bool":false},{"option":"1 E. coli/100ml","bool":false},{"option":"10 E. coli/100ml","bool":false},{"option":"0 E. coli/100ml","bool":true},{"option":"200 E. coli/100ml","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What determines how contaminated water is?","answers":[{"option":"Colour of the water","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of aquatic life","bool":false},{"option":"Amount of dissolved CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Amount of dirt in the water","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of faecal coliform","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is least likely to cause an attack of acute gout?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":true},{"option":"Loop diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"Thiazide diuretics","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclosporin","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A child presents to the clinic with joint pain, abdominal pain, and a rash on the buttocks. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudogout","bool":false},{"option":"Juvenile rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Henoch-Schonlein purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Gout","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is specific for SLE?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-ribonuclear antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-dsDNA antibodies","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-histone antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-Jo antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"Antinuclear antibodies","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 55-year-old female has been brought to the emergency room following severe lower back pain following a fall from standing height in the bathroom. A radiograph reveals fracture of the neck of femur. General examination reveals kyphosis and height loss. Which of the following investigations is the best choice for confirmation of the underlying disorder?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray left wrist anteroposterior view","bool":false},{"option":"Bone biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Radionuclide bone scan","bool":false},{"option":"DEXA scan of lumber spine and hip","bool":true},{"option":"X-ray hip joint","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A patient presents with lower back pain and uveitis. His X-ray shows a bamboo-like spine. What disease could he possibly have?","answers":[{"option":"Spinal fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":true},{"option":"Osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Disc herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the first-line treatment for osteoporosis?","answers":[{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false},{"option":"Denosumab","bool":false},{"option":"Raloxifene","bool":false},{"option":"Hormone replacement therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Bisphosphonates","bool":true}]},{"id":96,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 60-year-old female diagnosed with osteoporosis is prescribed a drug that binds to hydroxyapatite and decreases bone resorption. How do you take this drug?","answers":[{"option":"Take with 2 to 3 ounce of water","bool":false},{"option":"Take with 6 to 8 ounce of water","bool":true},{"option":"Take with orange juice","bool":false},{"option":"Take with food","bool":false},{"option":"Take and immediately lie down","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A patient was diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis 3 months back and prescribed methotrexate 10mg weekly, and prednisone 10mg daily. However, he fails to notice a significant improvement in his symptoms. Which of the following is the next step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Switch to another DMARD","bool":false},{"option":"Initiate pulse therapy of corticosteroid","bool":false},{"option":"Add another DMARD as combination therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Add an anti-TNF agent","bool":false},{"option":"Increase the dosage of methotrexate","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A patient recently diagnosed with rheumatoid arthritis is prescribed methotrexate 10mg weekly and corticosteroid 10 mg daily. He is followed up monthly, and the dose of methotrexate increased to 25mg but improvement fails to occur. After 6 months, the doctor concludes the medication regime to be ineffective. What is the next step in the management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Add an anti-TNF agent","bool":false},{"option":"Give high dose steroids and decrease gradually","bool":false},{"option":"Increase dosage of methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"RF and ACPA levels","bool":false},{"option":"Add another DMARD","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the most suitable drug for the treatment of chronic gout?","answers":[{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":false},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false},{"option":"Febuxostat","bool":false},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":true},{"option":"Colchicine","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common type of chondrosarcoma?","answers":[{"option":"Mesenchymal chondrosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Dedifferentiated chondrosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Conventional chondrosarcoma","bool":true},{"option":"Clear cell chondrosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tubular chondrosarcoma","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following appears as a stalked tumor of the bone?","answers":[{"option":"Osteochondroma","bool":true},{"option":"Chondrosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoma","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoid osteoma","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What of the following is referred to as a \"Gamekeeperâ€™s thumb\"?","answers":[{"option":"Monteggia's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Galeazzi's fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Injury to ulnar collateral ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Fracture of the thumb phalanges","bool":false},{"option":"Bennett's fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common complication of talus neck fracture?","answers":[{"option":"Nonunion","bool":false},{"option":"Avascular necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Varus malunion","bool":false},{"option":"Tibiotalar arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Subtalar arthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is a non-nitrogenous bisphosphonate?","answers":[{"option":"Alendronate","bool":false},{"option":"Risedronate","bool":false},{"option":"Pamidronate","bool":false},{"option":"Etidronate","bool":true},{"option":"Ibandronate","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A middle-aged man with no known co-morbid came with complaints of severe pain in 1st metatarsophalangeal (MTP) joint. The joint is red, hot, tender, swollen. Which of the following conditions could he most likely have?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Septic arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Juvenile rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute gout","bool":true},{"option":"Ankylosing spondylitis","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following antibodies are present in CREST syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Anti-dsDNA antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-histone antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-centromere antibody","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-Jo1 antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-topoisomerase antibody","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What joint is most commonly involved in pseudogout?","answers":[{"option":"Knee joint","bool":true},{"option":"Hip joint","bool":false},{"option":"Metatarsophalangeal joint","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical spine","bool":false},{"option":"Ankle joint","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the most common joint involvement in ankylosing spondylitis?","answers":[{"option":"Knee joint","bool":false},{"option":"Shoulder joint","bool":false},{"option":"Hip joint","bool":false},{"option":"Sacroiliac joint","bool":true},{"option":"Vertebral joint","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which function is impaired by the fracture in the midshaft of ulna and radius?","answers":[{"option":"Elbow extension","bool":false},{"option":"Supination and pronation","bool":false},{"option":"Wrist extension","bool":true},{"option":"Wrist flexion","bool":false},{"option":"Elbow flexion","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 58-year-old female presents with an inter-trochanteric fracture of the femur. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment for her?","answers":[{"option":"External fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Plaster cast and antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Hemi-arthroplasty","bool":false},{"option":"Internal fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Dynamic hip screw (DHS)","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of these metastatic bone tumors shows up as a solitary unifocal lesion?","answers":[{"option":"Lung","bool":false},{"option":"Colon","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Breast","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following inhibits bone resorption?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Parathyroid hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen/testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Tumor necrosis factor","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 30-year-old male was presented in a clinic with a suspected bone tumor epiphysis of the proximal tibia. X-ray shows an eccentric lytic area, giving a \"soap bubble\" involving appearance. Which of the following benign tumors has a hallmark of a soap bubble appearance?","answers":[{"option":"Chondroblastoma","bool":false},{"option":"Osteochondroma","bool":false},{"option":"Chondroma","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell tumor","bool":true},{"option":"Non-ossifying fibroma","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is considered the diagnostic test for osteoporosis?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D serum","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray lumbosacral spine","bool":false},{"option":"Bone scan","bool":false},{"option":"CT bony pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"DEXA scan","bool":true}]},{"id":115,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"How long after radiation exposure does leukemia develop?","answers":[{"option":"5 or more years","bool":true},{"option":"A few days","bool":false},{"option":"10 years","bool":false},{"option":"2 to 5 years","bool":false},{"option":"10 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following diseases is caused by inhalation of sugarcane dust?","answers":[{"option":"Siderosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":true},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is the basis to confirm the diagnosis of gout?","answers":[{"option":"Urate crystals in synovial fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Joint pain and redness","bool":false},{"option":"Renal stones","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperuricemia","bool":false},{"option":"Increased uric acid excretion in urine","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"An 18-month-old boy dies from an accidental overdose of acetaminophen. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient's death?","answers":[{"option":"Severe anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Liver failure","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory failure","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic stroke","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which one of the following statements is the most appropriate regarding the biological oxygen demand?","answers":[{"option":"It shows the amount of oxygen available for life to survive in water","bool":false},{"option":"It shows growth and oxygen demand of bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"It is the sum of polyvalent cations","bool":false},{"option":"It is the indicator of dissolved oxygen","bool":false},{"option":"It is the indicator of acidity","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 44-year-old man visits a physician with complaints of chronic productive cough. He has also developed dyspnea on mild exertion lately. Chest X-ray shows small irregular opacities most prominent in the upper poles of the lungs. The man has a history of working in coal mines for 5 years. Which of the following is the most likely disease the physician should suspect?","answers":[{"option":"Byssinosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bagassosis","bool":false},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":true},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"The arc welding affects the eyes causing intense conjunctivitis and keratitis. Welderâ€™s flash is caused by increased exposure to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ultraviolet radiation","bool":true},{"option":"Ionizing radiation","bool":false},{"option":"X-rays","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Radioactive isotopes","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department (OPD) for growth assessment. On examination, he is vitally stable with a height of 85 cm (2.7 ft) and a weight of 12 kg (26 lbs). The child also has frontal and parietal bossing, bowed legs, and prominent costochondral junctions. His serum calcium is found to be 10 mg/dl, alkaline phosphatase is 520 IU/L and serum vitamin D is 4 ng/ml. Which of the following is the most appropriate treatment choice?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D3 100,000 IU IM STAT","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D3 600,000 IU IM STAT","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D3 300,000 IU IM STAT","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium 500 mg once daily for 1 month","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin D 5 drops/day for 1 month","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs specifically inhibits uric acid synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Celecoxib","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroid","bool":false},{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which one of the following is a feature of osteoarthritis on an x-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Fracture of femoral condyles","bool":false},{"option":"Widening of joint space","bool":false},{"option":"Subchondral sclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Peri-articular osteopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Dislocation of knee joint","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a radiological feature of vitamin D deficiency?","answers":[{"option":"Osteophytes","bool":true},{"option":"Looser's zone","bool":false},{"option":"Rachitic rosary","bool":false},{"option":"Craniotabes","bool":false},{"option":"Greenstick fracture","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 30-year-old bodybuilder male patient presented to the outpatient department with a complaint of back pain, lower limb pain, and perineal anesthesia. What is the probable diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Cauda equina syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Lumbar disc herniation","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse myelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal stenosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar strain","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"A 25-year-old female patient who has six children and has been lactating her last child for 3 months presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of overall body aches, and difficulty in getting up from a sitting position. On investigation, she has hemoglobin of 11.2 g/dl, mean corpuscular volume: of 64 fL, and serum calcium level: of 8.1 mg/dl. What is the probable diagnosis of the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Thalassemia","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoarthritis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteopetrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Osteomalacia","bool":true},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What do you mean by biomagnification?","answers":[{"option":"The amount of oxygen in water which allow survival of aquatic species","bool":false},{"option":"Amount of oxygen required to nourish bacteria in water","bool":false},{"option":"Over nourishing of a body of stored water, by presence of phosphorus and nitrogen","bool":false},{"option":"The number of pollutants present in an environment","bool":false},{"option":"Persistent toxins or chemicals become increasingly concentrated as they move up the food chain","bool":true}]},{"id":129,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What is the definitive treatment for severe osteoarthritis?","answers":[{"option":"Osteotomy","bool":false},{"option":"Arthrodesis","bool":false},{"option":"Physiotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Total joint arthroplasty (replacement)","bool":true},{"option":"NSAIDs","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"4th-year/orthopedics/2019","question":"What type of electrolyte imbalance is seen after exercise?","answers":[{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypomagnesemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypercalcemia","bool":false}]}]
export default arr